Yanling Xu

UX / Product Designer

BIOGRAPHY

Coming from a background in research, economics, and design, I situate my work in the intersection of business, technology and user success. I'm always passionate about solving complex problems, system thinking and design that works well and does good.

EXPERIENCE

UX Designer / Genospace, Boston

Oct 2018 - Present

- Lead user research and product design effort on multiple new initiatives in the data management and the biomedical research product space from ideation to delivery to implementation
- Lead cross-team initiative to develop and implement Genospace Design System
- Collaborate as one of the core designer to explore, research, and design the EMR-EDC Integration platform

UX Design Intern / Motorola Solutions, Chicago

May 2018 - Sept 2018

- Led thorough stakeholder and market research on the safety and security landscape in K-12 and University contexts
- Designed and prototyped an end-to-end intelligent system by applying user-centric methods with 2 patents filed

Product Designer / Bentley University, Boston

Oct 2017 - May 2018

- Delivered 4 different projects in healthcare, government, and consumer product and service sectors with clients including National Science Foundation, TripAdvisor, and Brightcove.
- Facilitated design sprints, conducted heuristic evaluation, delivered vision prototypes using various prototyping techniques.

Research Associate / Institute for Social Research

May 2015 - Jul 2017

 Planned and executed qualitative and quantitative research tasks for nation wide longitudinal studies. Constructed databases and performed statistical analysis.



www.yanlingxu.com



+1 339-215-9432



yanlingxdesign@outlook.com

EDUCATION

MS, Human Computer Interaction

Sep 2017 - Dec 2018

Bentley University, Boston

BS, Mathematical Science & Economics

2012 - 2015

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor

TOOLS SKILLS	TOOL	S	S	K		ĺ			(
--------------	------	---	---	---	--	---	--	--	---	--

Designing	Formative Research
Sketch	User Interviews
Photoshop	Survey / Observation
Figma	Competitive Analysis
Adobe XD	Generative Research
Coding	Affinity Diagramming
Coding HTML / CS	
•	
HTML / CS	User Personas

Prototyping Summative Research

Principle Usability Testing
InVision Heuristic Evaluation
Framer X Cognitive Walkthrough

PATENTS

Dynamically Docking An Unmanned Aerial Vehicle

16/184043 (Docket No.PAT23218-US-PRI)

Method and System to Project Guidance to Building Occupants During An Emergency Situation

16/714996 (Docket No.PAT23753-US-PRI)